Cultural Festival
本字幕由诸神字幕组出品，仅供学习交流，禁止用于商业用途
Haunted House
Regarding our attraction
for the cultural festival,
Haunted House
では　文化祭の出し物ですが
更多中日双语字幕，尽在 www.kamigami.org 和微博&微信 @诸神字幕组
Haunted House
based on the results
of the committee meeting,
実行委員会の会議の結果
our class, 1-F, will be doing
the haunted house as we requested.
１-Ｆは希望通り　お化け屋敷ができることになりました
Hell yeah!
よっしゃ　やったぜ
競争率高かったもんな　お化け屋敷
Every class wanted the haunted house!
We would like to assign tasks now,
早速担当を決めていきたいと思うので
so please write your name on
the board if you see one you want.
希望があれば　黒板に名前を書いてください
Which one do you want?
どれやる？
What do you wanna do, Kicchan?
きっちゃんはどれがいい？
The cultural festival's a school event
that gets everyone especially excited.
文化祭といえば　学校行事の中でも半端なく盛り上がるイベントだ
There'll be lots of food stands, too.
模擬店もいろいろ出るらしいし
I can't wait. How about you, Tanaka?
今から楽しみだな　田中
He's erasing all traces of his presence!
半端なく気配を消している
The cultural festival...
文化祭といえば
A time when the entire school is enveloped
準備から開催に至るまで校内が謎の青春パワーに包まれる
in mysterious, youthful energy,
from preparation to the actual event.
The one ranked #1 on the list of school events
できれば参加したくない学校行事ランキング第１位として
that I don't want to participate in, right?
名高いあれでしょ
So that's what a cultural festival means to you?
お前の中ではそういう存在なんだな　文化祭
Yeah.
そう　だから面倒そうな仕事を任されないためにも
That's why, to avoid having
to do any troublesome work,
I've been training hard to conceal my presence,
こうして気配を消す練習　みっちりしてきた
for the past two weeks.
２週間も前から
Two whole weeks?
２週間もか
Talk about dedicated.
気合が違うな
If people with motivation take on all the work,
やる気のある人たちがガンガン仕事を取ってくれれば
俺のやることは何もなくなるはず
there shouldn't be anything for me to do.
Haunted
House
Tanaka-kun, Ohta-kun.
田中くん　太田くん
Haunted
House
Ghosts
Haunted
House
Ghosts
Haunted
House
Ghosts
Haunted
House
Ghosts
Haunted
House
Ghosts
Haunted
House
Ghosts
Yamane
Haunted
House
Ghosts
Yamane
Haunted
House
Ghosts
Endou
Yamane
Haunted
House
Ghosts
Chihara
Endou
Yamane
Haunted
House
Ghosts
Chihara
Endou
Yamane
Haunted
House
Ghosts
Chihara
Endou
Yamane
Haunted
House
Ghosts
Chihara
Endou
Yamane
Ghosts
Chihara
Endou
Yamane
Ghosts
Chihara
Endou
Yamane
The only roles left are for ghosts,
Ghosts
Chihara
Endou
Yamane
あと残ってるの　お化け役だけだから
Endou
Yamane
Chihara
Ghosts
Endou
Yamane
Chihara
Endou
Yamane
Chihara
Endou
Ghosts
so we'll leave those to you, okay?
二人ともよろしくね
Sorry! Everyone's so excited,
all the other tasks filled up right away.
ごめんね　みんなすごいやる気で　すぐ埋まっちゃって
We got the starring role.
主役　ゲットだな
Tanaka-kun
Is Always
Listless
After school I sit next to a window
眠たい放課後　窓から見下ろす
春風なびいて　ひと休み
And the spring breeze entices me to sleep
日听
gen & AB
翻译
颜歌＆沐沐
So I shut an eye against the dazzling world
眩しい世界に　片目を瞑れば
日校
小伍
校对
戚风＆Naga
While the sun makes the scenery dance upon my eyelids
时轴
WEI&和路雪
压制
wedy96
映し出す景色躍りだす
负责人
戚风
I whistle vaguely at the blue sky
頼りない口笛　青空に吹けば
足取りもちょっと軽くなる
And I get more of a spring in my step
I remove my earphones in a bustling corner of the city
騒がしい街角　イヤフォン外して
And look into the distance, where I hear a voice
見上げたら遠く声がする
Let's bask in the glowing sun
さぁ陽の光浴びてゆるやかに
Ever so gently
いつもの今日が始まる
Starting another day as usual
サンシャインと居眠りする
Napping in the sunshine
In this cozy place with you
心地いい場所　君の隣で
With all these feelings booming in my heart
優しく胸に響いてる
字幕
诸神字幕组
Episode 11
Tanaka-kun's
Cultural Festival
All right everyone, we're gonna give it
our all to scare the crap out of them!
よーし　全身全霊をかけてビビらせるぞー
Yeah!
I'll do my best to make scary ghost props!
頑張って怖いお化けの大道具作りますね
We're counting on you.
頼むな
Katou and Shimura,
construction's probably going to be tough,
加藤と志村も設営大変そうだが　頑張ってくれ
but good luck.
Just leave it to us.
任せとけって
The layout for the haunted house is done,
お化け屋敷の設計図ができたから打ち合わせしよっぜぃ
so let's have a meeting!
Got it.
そうだな
I wanna go home...
帰りたい
So I'm playing the role of ghost...
俺なんかがお化け役とは…
I'm not too confident in my acting skills.
演技にはあまり自信がないんだが　大丈夫だろうか
I hope it works out.
You'll be fine!
大丈夫大丈夫　そんな気張らず　楽しんでやろうぜ
Don't be so tense. Let's just have fun!
He's right, Ohta-kun!
そうですよ　太田くん
You'll be fine!
Oh, right...
大丈夫ですよ
そうだ　こういう時こそ特訓したあれを使ってフェードアウトすれば
You think so?
そうなのか
This is the perfect situation
to make use of my training,
Why are you so worried?
なに気にしてんのよ
Ohta! We need you to be strong!
太田　お前の力が必要なんだ
and fade out.
But...
しかし…
Look at Tanaka!
見ろ　田中を
He has no presence at all, just like a real ghost!
まるで本物のお化けみたいな気配のなさ
Amazing, Tanaka!
すげぇじゃん　田中
You've already practiced for this?!
なんだ　もう練習済みかよ
Just what I'd expect from Master!
さすが師匠です
You're totally gonna kill it!
いやー　期待の星だなぁ
どうしよう　太田　なんか特訓がアダに
What do I do now, Ohta?
My training has backfired on me...
At this point, you might as well just dive in.
もういっそ開き直って頑張れ
As long as you belong to a class,
you have to take on some kind of work.
クラスに所属している以上　何も仕事を担わないわけにもいかんからな
Besides, take a look, Tanaka.
それに　よく見てみろ　田中
I brought all the black curtains I could find!
暗幕　ありったけ持ってきたぞ
ペンキ足りないみたい　誰か買ってきて
We don't have enough paint.
Can someone go buy more?
Yeah. I've already asked the teacher
about that, so we're fine.
うん　それを先生に相談してあるから大丈夫
他の係りより　お化け役の方が楽かもしれんぞ
Playing a ghost might be
easier than the other jobs.
言われてみれば…
Now that you mention it...
I see...
そっか
Now that I know I got the easiest task,
一番楽な役ってわかったら
I'm beginning to think I might be able
to sort of, maybe try my best.
それなりに頑張ろうとしてみたりとかもできそうな気がしてきたよ
Can't you just say you'll try your best?
素直に頑張るとは言わんのか
Having an actual
out-of-body experience
最終的に　リアル幽体離脱で魂だけ参戦とか良さそう
so only my spirit has to participate
might not be a bad idea.
体は家で休めるし　お化け屋敷的にもおいしいし
My body could relax at home,
and it'd be perfect for the haunted house.
Ohta...
太田ー
Uh, just do the best you can
in your living body, okay?
いや　そこは生身で頑張れる範囲で頼む
Tanaka, you're good at hiding your presence,
田中は気配を消すのがうまいから　物陰から突然現れて脅かす系の役を頼む
so you can jump out suddenly to scare people.
Okay.
オッケー
Let's try a simulation.
ちょっとシミュレーションしてみようぜ
It'll look something like this...
こんな感じで
Tanaka, you stand there.
田中はそこに立って
Whoa, this is scary...
わぁ　怖いな
Tanaka, he's here! The customer is here!
田中　来てる　もう来てる　客
もう来てたの　びっくりした
You're here already? What a surprise...
Welcome.
いらっしゃい
He's the one who's surprised,
and he gave me a warm welcome...
脅かす側が逆に驚いて　しかも手厚く出迎えた
Um...
えーと…
Urashimaya?
うらしまやー
Wrong line! I'm not Urashima Taro at Ryugu-jo!
決め台詞決まってない　竜宮城か
He's no good at anything
other than hiding his presence.
気配を消す以外全部ダメだなぁ
How about a ghost inside a well?
じゃあ　井戸の中のお化けはどうですか
When a customer walks by,
the lighting crew can put a spotlight on him.
お客さんが来たら　照明係りの人が照らしてくれるらしいので
He can just sit there!
座っているだけでいいそうです
Well (temporary)
Looking good.
いい感じだなぁ
This will be your post, Master!
師匠はここで決まりですね
What's wrong, Ohta?
どうした　太田
心配だな
I'm concerned.
If we use this setup, I'm afraid...
この感じだとたぶん…
It'll be fine. You're such a worrywart, Ohta.
大丈夫だって　心配性だな　太田は
Okay, I'll turn on the spotlight!
じゃあ　ライトを照らしてみます
...Tanaka will fall asleep.
田中は寝るぞ
What the—?!
なんだと…
Whoa, that was fast!
わぁ　寝るの早っ
It's dark, cramped,
and there's no one else around.
「暗闇　狭い　放置」と揃っているからな
Those are ideal conditions
for his sleeping spots.
ベスト安眠スペースだ
We have no choice.
こうなったらやむをえん
Eyelid eyes!
まぶた目だー
Now Tanaka can do his job even while he's asleep.
これなら　田中も寝たまま任務を遂行できるぞ
This might make people laugh
after the surprise wears off, though.
けどこれ　あとからじわじわ笑えてくるかも
This is the first thing they'll see when they walk in,
お化け屋敷入って最初の仕掛けだし　もっと単純に怖い方がいいかもなぁ
so something that's just
typically scary might be better.
Huh? Sorry.
あれ　ごめん
俺寝てた？
Did I fall asleep?
What the heck? That's really scary!
なにそれ　超怖い
Nice, Tanaka!
ナイス　田中
Next, we'll use this.
次は　これだな
Hands popping out from an old shoji door!
ボロボロの障子から突然手が出てくる仕掛け
That sounds fun! I wanna try!
おお　面白そう　俺もやってみたい
出るとわかっても結構びっくりするなぁ
Even when you know it's coming, it's quite a shock.
This is something even I can do.
これなら俺にもできそうだ
How's this?
どうだ
Uh...
Yeah...
Your default setting is a little high.
太田の場合　初期設定のポジションが高すぎる
Huh?
Unfortunately, your hands are outside
the average person's field of vision.
残念だが　普通の人には手が視界に入ってこない
You're so tall...
でかいからな
No good, huh?
ダメか
Tanaka-kun!
田中くん
演劇部から衣装を借りてきたから　ちょっと着てみてくれる？
I borrowed this costume from the drama club.
Can you try it on?
'Kay...
はい
There.
Oh, good. The size looks about right.
よかった　サイズは大丈夫だね
Since you're a ghost,
should it be right-over-left instead,
お化け役だし　死装束ってことで
to indicate you're wearing a burial kimono?
襟合わせ逆にした方がいいのかな　リアリティを追求するなら
You know, for realism's sake.
I see...
なるほど
Like this?
こうか
He just naturally, so naturally,
exposed his bare body!
今ナチュラルに　ナチュラルに裸体を
It's okay! He was wearing underwear!
大丈夫　パンツははいてた　パンツははいてたから
He was wearing underwear!
Is this right?
これで合ってる？
Uh... Yeah...
I ended up being left with the most
important part, the grand finale.
結局　ラストの一番の見せ場を任されてしまった
I wonder if I can handle it...
できるだろうか
Wow, that's amazing.
すごいじゃん
You look very imposing, so you'll do fine.
太田迫力ありそうだし　大丈夫だよ
よう
Yo.
Echizen...
越前
I heard 1-F is doing a haunted house.
１-Ｆはお化け屋敷するんだってな
もしかしてお前らお化け役か
Let me guess, you guys are playing the ghosts?
You're both more into this than you look.
見かけによらずやる気じゃねぇか
Essan! Ya finish the sign?
えっさん　看板できた？
Yeah, it's drying right now! I'll bring it later!
おー　今乾かし中　あとで持ってく
Got it!
わかったー
よかった
I'm glad...
越前さん　宮野さん以外にも友達いたんだね
Echizen-san, you have friends
other than Miyano-san.
Yeah. I thought you were
the lone wolf in your class.
ああ　てっきりクラスでは一匹狼かと
C-Cut it out!
なっ　や…やめろ
Don't gimme that look like
I'm your damn kid or something!
そんな我が子を見守るみたい目で見んな
Heave!
えっさ　ほいさ
Ho!
Heave!
えっさ　ほいさ
Ho!
Whew...
よいしょっと
All right!
よっしゃー
All done!
完成
It looks just like the real deal!
すごく本格的だよ
Great work, Katou-kun and Shimura-kun.
お疲れ様　加藤くん　志村くん
Oh, don't mention it.
いやー　それほどでも
To me, this is nothing.
俺にかかれば　これくらい
みんなが頑張ったからだよ
It's all thanks to everyone's hard work!
Room of Terror
じゃあ　人を入れて　予行演習してみよう
Let's bring some people in for a rehearsal!
Ghost crew, please stand by!
お化け役の人　スタンバイ頼む
A bath...
風呂だ
A bath.
お風呂
It literally just looks like a bath.
どう見ても風呂
It's pretty comfortable.
結構　落ち着く
N-No problems here...
と…特に問題ないな
Scary!
こえー
Why are you getting scared by this?
お前かよ
Okay, all that's left is Ohta's grand finale.
さて　残すは太田担当のラストの見せ場だな
I present the construction
crew's pièce de résistance.
ここは設営班めっちゃ気合入れて作ったかんね
Behold!
ほら　ここが１-Ｆお化け屋敷　メインステージだ
The main stage of 1-F's haunted house!
Isn't it awesome?! Isn't it terrifying?!
ヤバくねぇ　めっちゃ怖くねぇ
Ohta, you'll lie in wait right here,
太田はここで待機してて
and when someone comes close, move suddenly!
人が近づいてきたら　ガバーって動いてな
Yep. People will think you're all tied up,
縄で縛られてると思いきや襲ってきたっていう不意打ちな感じで
but then you start chasing them
out of the blue, taking them by surprise!
Amazing! It's like a real haunted house!
すごい　本物のお化け屋敷みたいだね
Exit
Okay, let's start bringing customers in.
よーし　じゃあ　客役入れるよ
お化け役　しっかり頼むな
Ghost crew, we'll be counting on you!
What's wrong, Ohta? Why did you come out?
どうしたの　太田
なんで出てきちゃった
We're gonna rehearse,
so you need to get back to your post.
練習するから　定位置にいてもらわないと
I'm sorry...
すまない　言い出せなかったんだが
I couldn't say it,
but I'm actually...
実は俺…
terrified of ghosts.
お化けが怖いんだ
With that face?!
その顔で？
Tanaka-kun Is Always Listless
じゃ…じゃあ　なんでお化け役を引き受けたりなんか
Th-Then why did you agree to play a ghost?
You should've told us.
言ってくれりゃいいのに
いや　俺のわがままで　担当を変わってもらうのも悪いし
I felt bad that someone would have to
take my place for my own selfish reasons...
And honestly, I thought a
cultural festival haunted house
正直　文化祭のお化け屋敷なら
would look more fantasy-like,
so it wouldn't bother me.
もっとファンシーな作りで　大丈夫かと
I was too naïve.
甘く見ていた
My knees are actually weak just from
walking through it to get out here.
実は今　中を通ってきただけで　腰が抜けている
With that face?!
その顔で？
Takoyaki
じゃ　太田無理じゃん
Ohta can't do this, then!
What should we do for the grand finale?
ラストの見せ場どうすんの
Takoyaki
本番　明日…
The festival is tomorrow...
Takoyaki
わかりました　私がなんとかします
I understand.
I'll resolve this one way or another.
Cultural Festival
~ Grab! The Light of Youth!! ~
Wait, Essan!
ちょっと　えっさん
I can't! I can't do this anymore!
私もうやだもうムリ
C-Calm down. We're almost at the exit!
お…落ち着け　後ちょっとで出口だから
Look there...
あそこ…
I'm a cat girl demon!
妖怪猫女です
お前ら全員　呪ってやるです
I'll curse you all!
Y... Y...
You're waaay too cute, Myaano!
可愛いすぎか　みゃーのー
She's so cute!
Send me that picture later?
その写真　後で僕にも送ってよ
What's going on?!
おかしいです
いいよ
The harder I try, the more people smile!
さっきから頑張れば頑張るほどお客さんが笑顔です
オチのあるニュータイプお化け屋敷として　ウケてるな
I think people are enjoying our new type
of haunted house with comic relief at the end.
これはこれでよかったかもなぁ
All's well that ends well, I guess!
Reception
Ohta-kun!
太田くん
How's the reception work going?
受付大丈夫？
No problems here.
ああ　問題ない
I'm so grateful to Miyano for taking my place.
宮野が代わってくれて　助かったぞ
あのね　今出口でお客さんにアンケート書いてもらってるんだけど
Hey, we're having people
fill out a survey after they exit,
and they voted Tanaka-kun the scariest.
一番怖かったって票が多いの　田中くんなんだよ
Seriously? That's amazing!
マジか　すごいな
I see... I won't be able to see him
at work since I can't go in there,
そうか　中に入れず　雄姿は拝めないが
but Tanaka must be working
extra hard to make up for me.
俺がリタイアした分　頑張ってくれてるんだな　田中
Yeah. We should support him in any way we can!
だね　私たちもサポート頑張ろう
On break!
1-F Haunted House
Will be resuming at 13:30
On break!
Okay, let's take a one-hour break!
よーし　今から１時間休憩
On break!
はーい
We'll resume at 13:30. Don't be late, everyone!
１３時半再開だから　みんな遅れないようになあ
What do you wanna eat?
何食べる
I heard there's a crêpe stand.
クレープ屋さんあるんだって
Wanna go?
行ってみよっか
Where's Tanaka?
あれ　田中？
Tanaka!
田中　教室に鍵かけるから　出てこーい
We're locking up the classroom, so come on out!
We're taking a break until 13:30.
１３時半まで休憩な
If you wanna check out the
food stands, now's the time.
回りたいとこあったら　今のうちに行っとけよ
Welcome!
They expect me to take
a break with all this ruckus?
この騒がしい空間のどこで休めと
とりあえず太田見つけて　どこか静かな場所に連れてってもらおう
First things first. I should find Ohta
and have him take me somewhere quiet.
Sorry, Ohta-kun,
but the decoration fell from up there...
ごめん　太田くん
あそこの上の飾りが取れちゃってさ
Oh, leave it to me.
ああ　任せろ
Ohta, can you give us a hand, too?
太田　こっちも頼めるか
Yeah, sure.
おお　わかった
Looks like this is a bad time...
今　声かけるのも悪いし
Oh, well.
仕方ない　なんとか自力で休めそうな場所を探すか
I guess I'll have to find
someplace to rest on my own.
Maid Café
Caramel Ribbon
Please? Can you take my place for just 30 minutes?
Maid Café
Caramel Ribbon
お願い　３０分だけでいいから代わって
Maid Café
Caramel Ribbon
I really want to see the drama club's play!
Maid Café
Caramel Ribbon
どーうしても演劇部の劇見たいの
Jeez, fine...
ったく　しょうがねぇな　３０分だけだぞ
Only for 30 minutes, though!
Thanks!
ありがとう
Welcome to Caramel Ribbon!
ようこそ　キャラメルリボンへ
Will it be a table for one, sir?
お客様　一名様でございますか
Go home...
帰れ
帰れよ
Go home...
帰れよ　今見たことは全て忘れろー
Go home! Forget everything you just saw!
Essan, calm down!
えっさん　落ち着いてー
It's a ghost!
お化けだ
How scary!
怖い
Whoops...
しまった
It's too late now,
but this costume makes me stand out.
今更だけど　この格好　結構目立つ
I should probably hide somewhere.
どこかに隠れた方がよさそう
痛っ
Ow.
Tanaka isn't back yet...
田中帰ってこないな
Yeah.
すまん　俺も見ていなくて
Sorry. I wasn't watching him.
However!
だが　あいつの脱走は想定済
I already accounted for such a possibility.
Katou! Go change!
加藤　着替えてこい
Roger!
ラージャー
Yay, I get to be a ghost!
やった　お化け
You arranged for a replacement?
代わりを準備してあるのか　さすがだな
Talk about thorough.
I didn't anticipate needing one for you, though...
太田のは想定外だったけどな
Sorry...
すまん
Reporting a lost child.
迷子のお知らせです
A little boy about three years old,
wearing a blue T-shirt,
青いＴシャツを着た３歳くらいの男の子が職員室でお待ちです
is waiting in the faculty room.
If you have any information on this boy,
お心当たりのあるお客様は至急職員室までお越しください
please come to the faculty room.
太田　放送がかけられる前に田中回収してきてくれるか
Ohta, can you go retrieve Tanaka before
they make an announcement about him?
If people find out our ghost is lost in the school,
お化けが校内で迷子だなんて知られちゃ
ますます和み度が加速するぞ　このお化け屋敷
our haunted house's beautiful,
hard-earned reputation's gonna tank.
そうだな　行ってこよう
You're right... I'll go now.
So many people everywhere, as I expected.
やはり　どこも人が多いな
This crowd density will tire
Tanaka out in two seconds flat.
田中なら２秒でぐったりしてしまう人口密度だ
Shaved Ice
Melon
I'd better find him quick.
Shaved Ice
Melon
早く見つけてやらんと
Shaved Ice
Melon
Strawberry
Shaved Ice
Melon
Strawberry
Shaved Ice
Melon
Strawberry
Shaved Ice
Melon
Strawberry
Shaved Ice
Melon
Strawberry
Shaved Ice
Melon
Strawberry
Shaved Ice
Melon
Strawberry
Shaved Ice
Melon
Strawberry
Shaved Ice
Melon
Strawberry
Shaved Ice
Melon
Strawberry
Shaved Ice
Melon
Strawberry
Shaved Ice
Melon
Strawberry
Shaved Ice
Melon
Strawberry
Shaved Ice
Melon
Strawberry
Shaved Ice
Melon
Strawberry
Shaved Ice
Melon
Strawberry
Shaved Ice
Melon
Strawberry
Shaved Ice
Melon
Strawberry
Shaved Ice
Melon
Strawberry
Shaved Ice
Melon
Strawberry
Shaved Ice
Melon
Strawberry
Shaved Ice
Melon
Strawberry
Shaved Ice
Melon
Strawberry
Shaved Ice
Melon
Strawberry
Shaved Ice
Melon
Strawberry
Shaved Ice
Melon
Strawberry
Shaved Ice
Melon
Strawberry
Shaved Ice
Melon
Strawberry
Shaved Ice
Melon
Strawberry
Shaved Ice
Melon
Strawberry
Shaved Ice
Melon
Strawberry
Shaved Ice
Melon
Strawberry
Shaved Ice
Melon
Strawberry
Shaved Ice
Melon
Strawberry
Shaved Ice
Melon
Strawberry
Shaved Ice
Melon
Strawberry
Shaved Ice
Melon
Strawberry
Shaved Ice
Melon
Strawberry
Shaved Ice
Melon
Strawberry
Shaved Ice
Melon
Strawberry
Shaved Ice
Melon
Strawberry
Shaved Ice
Melon
Strawberry
Shaved Ice
Melon
Strawberry
Tanaka!
田中
I'm coming...
今
to save you!
助けに行くからな
Do not use the rooftop
during the cultural festival
No good...
ダメだ
I came all the way here as my last hope.
全ての望みをかけてここまで来たっていうのに
This world no longer has any place
where I can rest in peace.
もはやこの世に安息の地などない
Black Curtains
Store in chemistry room
Nice...
This is taking longer than I thought.
思ったより手間取ってしまったな
I didn't expect to encounter so many temptations.
まさか　あんなに大量の誘惑が立ちはだかっているとは
Hey, Tanaka! If you're here, answer me!
おい　田中　いたら返事しろ
Tanaka?
田中
Tanaka?!
田中か
O...
Oh...
Ohh...
Ohhhtaaa...
太田…
Huh?
あれ
Hey, Ohta...
おーい　太田
どうしたの　大丈夫？
What's wrong? Are you okay?
It looks like Ohta's in trouble,
but I can't carry him by myself.
太田ピンチっぽいけど　俺一人じゃ運べないし
I shouldn't just leave him here
while I go get help, either.
ここに置いたまま　人を呼びに行くのも心配
All I can do is wait until someone comes.
大人しく助けが来るのを待つしか
Wait...
あれ　そういえば今　何時なんだろう
What time is it right now, anyway?
It feels like it's only been about ten minutes,
体感的には１０分くらいだから　まだ大丈夫かな
so I guess we're still fine...
Whoa! This is where they've been?
こんなところにいた
Hey, wake up, Tanaka! Ohta!
おい　起きろ　田中　太田
We're starting to pack up!
片付け始まってるぞ
That thing! Where did that thing go?!
あれは　あれはどこに
Are you still half-asleep?
寝ぼけてんのか
さっさと片付けて打ち上げするぞ
Let's finish packing up and have a party.
Shimura... Katou...
志村　加藤
Huh? What's up, you two?
あれ　どうしたの　二人とも
あっ　お化け役
The ghost role...
I took over. Now that was fun!
俺がやっといた　面白かった
Sorry to slip out midway.
すまん　途中で抜けたままになって
ごめん
Sorry...
Nah, you guys worked hard all morning,
so don't worry about it.
午前中は頑張ってくれたし　いいよ
But you do need to help pack up!
でも　片付けは手伝えよ
Got it.
わかった
Okay...
Good work, everyone! Cheers!
お疲れ様です　乾杯
Cheers!
乾杯
Tanaka-kun Is Always Listless
おっはよう
Nothing's more relaxing than a typical day.
やっぱり日常が落ち着く
It's true...
ほんとなんですよ
They said there was a
white shadow in the pictures
文化祭で写真部の撮った写真に白い人影が写ってたって
the Photography Club
took during the festival.
Kicchan said there are rumors that it appeared
空き教室にも出たって噂があるってきっちゃんたちも言ってた
in the empty classroom, too.
What?
なに
I knew it.
やはりか
信じたくなかったが　本当にあったんだな
I didn't want to believe it, but they're true...
The school ghost stories...
学校の怪談というやつは
Consecrated Salt
You should stay away from the rooftop.
屋上には近づかん方がいいぞ　俺もあそこで見た
That's where I saw it!
Really? Then I might have seen it, too.
マジで？　じゃ俺も見たかも
Here, take this pile of salt!
ほら　塩もっとけ
Okay.
How scary...
怖いね
Everyday life is like a bothersome cat
BON-BON　いつもの　いたずら猫みたい
How I wish I could ignore it and do as I please
自然体で　ワガママしたい
I discreetly retreat into my own world of music
気ままミュージック　こっそりノリノリで
空想なら得意かも
Maybe I have a talent for daydreaming
いわゆる幸せ　それってなぁに？
That so-called happiness
What exactly is it?
I tried acting on my own desires
好きなこと　とことん　やってみて
わかるのかなぁ
Will I understand it now?
Dramatic listlessness
BON-BON　ドラマチック
I want to put my life into its hands
「そこそこ」が希望
ポジティブチケット　持ってたいね
Maybe a positive attitude is better
精一杯なら　正解なのかな
Is trying my best the right thing to do?
I can't hold a poker face
ポーカーフェイスは苦手です
Everyday life makes me dizzy
グルグルしちゃうね
BON-BON　KUBBIDYU
My dear listlessness
Once more
もう一回
My dear listlessness
BON-BON　KUBBIDYU
A girlfriend?! Him?!
女？　あいつに？
大人の階段登っちまうとは何事だ
How dare you take the first step up
the stairway to adulthood before me?!
何も言うなです
Don't say a word.
My feminine appeal is gonna burst!
こりゃあ私の女子力が火を噴くよ
いきなりこんなことをお前に言うのもなんだが
I know it's weird to ask this
of you out of the blue, but...
Next Episode
Tanaka-kun's
Happiness
Next time, Episode 12:
次回　第十二話「田中くんのしあわせ」
Tanaka-kun's Happiness.